(忆往昔)
-你确定是吸血鬼吗  -毫无疑问
- You're sure it's vampires?  - Definitely.
它们的始祖在组建一支军队
Their Alpha's building an army.
他们不再惧怕我们了
We don't scare them anymore.
我是你外公
I'm your grandfather.
萨穆埃尔
Samuel?
你不是已经死了么
We all thought you were dead.
我们觉得是救了萨姆的东西复活了我
We're guessing whatever pulled Sam up pulled me down.
不管它是什么  我们都成了它的一部分
So, whatever this is, we're both a part of it.
但你们不知道它是什么
But you don't know what that is.
迪恩  你没事吧  是萨姆  鲍比
Dean, you all right? It's Sam, Bobby.
他有点儿不一样了  我觉得他不太对劲
He's just -- he's different. Something's not right to me.
他怎么了
What is wrong with him?
我不知道  迪恩  真抱歉
I don't know, Dean. I'm sorry.
像是你故意让他变成吸血鬼的
Almost like you let him get turned.
你想找人打入内部
Get a man on the inside,
好帮我们找到吸血鬼始祖
help us find that Alpha vamp we've been looking for?
你觉得我会让我亲哥哥这样冒险
You think I'd do something like that, risk my own brother?
我还有你
You got my back.
不管发生什么  我都可以指望你
No matter what happens, I can always count on you,
对吧  小萨姆
Right, Sammy?
当然了  迪恩
Yeah. Of course, Dean.
你到底是什么东西  你不是人类
What are you? You're not human.
求你了  听我解释
Please, just let me explain.
见鬼的我干嘛要相信你
Why the hell should I believe anything you say?
我的确出了问题  很不对劲
There's something wrong with me, really wrong.
我需要帮助
I need help.
(如今)
没错  他看起来很糟糕
You're right. He looks terrible.
是你干的
You did this?
小卡
Cass?
怎么...  放开我
What's -- let me go.
-他有发烧吗  -你有吗
- Has he been feverish? - Have you?
没有  怎么了
No. Why?
他有没有过胡言乱语的情况
Is he speaking in tongues?
你有没有过胡言乱语的情况
Are you speaking in tongues?
没有  你干嘛...
No. What are you...
你是在给我看病吗
Are you diagnosing me?
你最好希望他能看出个所以然来
You better hope he can.
你真觉得这...
You really think that this is --
怎么  你真觉得有个诊所
What, you think that there's a clinic out there
专门治疗"地狱后遗症"是么
for people who just pop out of hell wrong?
他问你答
He asks, you answer!
不许废话  懂了吗
Then you shut your hole. You got it?
你每天睡多久
How much do you sleep?
我不睡觉
I don't.
完全不睡吗
At all?
我回来之后就不睡觉了
Not since I got back.
你难道就不觉得
And it never occurred to you
这事儿有点奇怪么
that there might be something off about that?!
当然有  迪恩
Of course it did, Dean.
我  我只是没告诉你
I-I just never told you.
-怎么了  -萨姆
- What? - Sam...
你现在有什么感觉
What are you feeling now?
我觉得我鼻子断了
I feel like my nose is broken.
不  那是身体上的  我是问你的感觉
No, that's a physical sensation. How do you feel?
-我觉得  -内心的感受
- Well, I think -- - Feel.
我...  不知道
I...Don't know.
怎么了
What? Uh...
-这会让你不太舒服  -什么
- This will be unpleasant. - What --
咬着它忍耐下吧
Bite down on this.
如果有某个地方能让你感到宽心
If there's someplace that you find soothing,
那就在你脑海中
you should go there.
想象你正身临其境
In your mind.
有啥发现吗
Did you find anything?
没
No.
算是个好消息吗
So that's good news?
恐怕不是
I'm afraid not.
生理上  他非常健康
Physically, he's perfectly healthy.
然后呢
Then what?
他的灵魂有问题
It's his soul.
它消失了
It's gone.
我... 很抱歉
I'm s-- I'm sorry.
再说一遍  当我是五岁小孩好了
One more time, like I'm 5.
这是什么意思  你说他没有...
What do you mean, he's got no --
不知为何  萨姆复活之后
Somehow, when Sam was resurrected,
他就没有了灵魂
it was without his soul.
那它在哪儿呢
So, where is it?
我猜是...
My guess is...
它还在封印米迦勒和路西法的牢笼里
still in the cage with Michael and Lucifer.
那  他还是萨姆吗
So, is he even still Sam?
你提出了一个很有趣的哲学问题
Well, you pose an interesting philosophical question.
那就把他的灵魂找回来
Well, then, just get it back.
-迪恩  -你都可以把我救出来
- Dean. - Well, you pulled me out.
当初救你牺牲了好几位天使
It took several angels to rescue you,
而且那时候看守也不是很严密
and you weren't nearly as well guarded.
萨姆的灵魂在路西法的牢笼里
Sam's soul is in Lucifer's cage.
这就有所不用了  是非常不同
There's a difference, a big difference.
不可能成功的
It's not possible.
好吧  肯定有办法的
Okay, well, there's got to be a way.
-你们到底要不要给我松绑  -不要
- So, are you gonna untie me? - No.
听着  我不会...
Listen, I'm not gonna --
萨姆  我怎么可能
Sam, how the hell
让你走出这个房间
am I even supposed to let you out of this room?
迪恩  我不是精神病
Dean, I'm not some psycho.
我不想让你受到伤害
I didn't want you to get hurt.
我只是想阻止那些吸血鬼
I was just trying to stop the vamps.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不会再发生这样的事了
It won't ever happen again.
放开我吧
Please let me go.
-你开玩笑的是吧 -那你要怎样
-You're kidding, right? -Well, what are you gonna do,
把我永远关在这里么
just keep me locked up in here forever?
我倒觉得那样没什么不好
You say that like it's a bad thing.
好吧  好吧  我懂了
Okay, fine, look, I get it.
我明白了  迪恩  我错了
I get it, Dean. I was wrong.
但是我告诉你  我想恢复正常
But I'm telling you I-I'm trying to get right.
我还是我
It's still me.
-是吗  -是的
- Is it? - Yes.
放开我吧
So just let me go.
门儿都没有
No way in hell.
我也不想事情变成这样
I didn't want it to come to this.
你不能把我关起来  迪恩
You're not gonna hold me, Dean --
关这儿不行  关避难屋里不行  都不行
Not here, not in a panic room, not anywhere.
我没有灵魂  你又摆脱不掉我
You're stuck with the soulless guy,
所以你就跟我合作吧
so you might as well work with me.
让我们搞定这事
Let's fix this.
我会监视你的一举一动
I'm gonna be watching every move you make.
好的
Fine.
确实应该如此
Sounds about right to me.
小卡  帮他治疗下伤口
Cass, clean him up.
如果我们想搞清楚你的灵魂是怎么回事
All right, if we're gonna figure out what happened to your soul,
那就得先知道谁把你拉出地狱的
then we need to find who yanked you out.
你说你不知道
You say you don't know?
不知道
No idea.
那就一个一个来
Then we start a list.
如果复活一个人不是易事
If it's so hard to spring someone out of the box,
那谁才拥有这种力量
then who's got that kind of muscle?
我不知道
I don't know.
关于复活  你一点记忆都没有吗
You have no memory of your resurrection?
我在一片田野里醒来  我就知道这么多
I woke up in a field. That's all I got.
毫无头绪吗
No clues? None?
有一个
I've got one.
外公办烧烤聚会  竟然也不电邮邀请我们
Gramps throw a barbecue, leave us off the e-vite list?
萨姆
Sam!
-迪恩  -你好  小贱货
- Dean. - Hello, Newman.
头儿呢
Where's the man?
别客气快进来
Come right on in.
我有点事儿想问你
Need to ask you a few questions.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你复活那天  发生了什么事
The day you got back, what happened?
我早就说过了啊
We've been over this.
给我们家小翅膀帮手再说说
Well, recap it for our wingman.
你就是卡西迪奥
This Castiel?
你比我想象的更消瘦
You're scrawnier than I pictured.
这只是一副皮囊
This is a vessel.
我的真身和你们的
My true form is approximately
克莱斯勒大厦一样大
the size of your Chrysler Building.
行啦  行啦  别炫耀了
All right, all right, quit bragging.
你死了  然后呢
So, you were dead, and...
然后我就突然身在埃山街上了
And, pow, I was on Elton Ridge.
具体过程和原因都不清楚
Don't know how. Don't know why.
各位  我全部坦白了
I got nothing to hide, guys.
你介不介意小卡复查一遍
Well, you mind if Cass here double-checks?
没事没事
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's okay. It's okay.
-没事  -搞什么啊
- It's okay. - What the hell?
天使体腔大搜查
Angel cavity search.
我没事  克里斯蒂安  你出去吧
I'm fine, Christian. Just give us a minute.
-但是  -你回避一下
- But -- - just give us a minute.
刚刚那是搞什么啊
What the hell was that about?
他的灵魂完整无缺
His soul is intact.
什么
What?
我当然有...
Of course I have a --
萨姆  怎么了
What's going on, Sam?
将我拉上来的那位
Whatever dragged me out...
把我的灵魂落下了
left a piece behind.
你事先知道吗
Did you know?
不知道  但是我
No, but I...
我知道有点不对劲  我
I knew it was something. I...
萨姆  你是出色的猎魔人  但是
You're a hell of a hunter, Sam, but...
实话实说  有时候你真吓人
the truth is, sometimes you scare me.
那这事儿怎么办  怎么处理
So, what's the deal here? How do we fix this?
我们怎么拿回他的灵魂
How do we get his soul back?
还不知道  但我们必须把它找回来
We don't know yet, but we have to.
我当然会助你们一臂之力
Well, I'm here to help, of course.
你们有何线索
What leads you working?
除了从你这查之外  毫无头绪
A bunch of dead ends and you.
那我们去寻找线索
Well, then, we'll just have to dig.
萨姆  迪恩
Sam, Dean...
我得回去了
I have to get back.
你不管我们啦
You're leaving?
我正身处天堂内战之中
I'm in the middle of a civil war.
你最好回去找找有什么能帮助萨姆的办法
You better tear the attic up, find something to help Sam.
当然  你们的事儿最重要
Of course. Your problems always come first.
我会和你们保持联络
I'll be in touch.
本来想叫他留下喝杯啤酒的
Would've asked him to stick around for a beer.
外面那读书俱乐部咋回事
So, what's with the book club outside?
正在组织一场猎魔
Putting together a hunt.
一次猎魔而已  怎么这么多人
That's a lot of guys for one hunt.
你找到他了  对吧
You found him, didn't you?
谁
Who?
他有吸血鬼始祖的线索了
He's got a lead on the Alpha vamp.
是吗
Do you?
可能吧
Maybe.
没错
Yeah.
你怎么查到的
How'd you track him down?
自有妙招
We're good.
就这样吗  "自有妙招"
That's all I get? "We're good"?
什么时候行动
When's the run?
黎明
Dawn.
你为什么不叫上我
You didn't call me? Why?
因为我
'cause of me.
你不是很信任我  是吧
You don't trust me very much, do you?
特别是在这种重要的猎魔活动时
Especially when it comes to big game like this.
不是的
That's not true.
那好啊  我们要加入
Okay, well, then, we're in.
别介意  但是
No offense, but --
你就是不相信我咯
So you don't trust me.
不  我只是不了解你
No, I just don't know you.
不像了解萨姆那么了解你
Not like I know Sam.
好吧
All right.
你发号施令
You call the plays.
我百分百遵命
100%. I'm here to listen.
你啥时候这么听话过
Since when?
吸血鬼的始祖哎
Big daddy bloodsucker?
我可不想错过好戏
I ain't gonna miss that.
但这是你的活儿
But this is your deal.
对吧  我懂的
Okay? I get it.
我会听从你的指令  我相信你
I'll follow your lead. I trust you.
我不相信他
I don't trust him.
他有所隐瞒
Dude's hiding something.
-什么  -我能感觉到
- What? - I can feel it.
要不是你现在没有灵魂  你也能感觉到
And if you weren't robo-Sam, you'd feel it, too.
怎样啊
What?
就是  你
Just...You.
你说你不相信家人
Saying you don't trust family.
我们接近他  打入内部
Look, we hang close, we blend in,
看看能发现什么
we see what we can pick up.
你觉得萨穆埃尔和我的灵魂有关吗
You think Samuel's connected to this whole soul thing?
我还是觉得他是唯一的线索
I still think he's the only lead we got.
迪恩  你迷路了吗
You lost, Dean?
想打个电话  需要一点私人空间
Had to make a phone call. Just needed some privacy.
萨穆埃尔上锁的办公室  真够隐秘啊
Samuel's locked office is pretty private.
没锁上啊
Wasn't locked.
你打给谁呢
Who you calling?
你的妻子  告诉她我今晚过不去了
Your wife. Let her know I'm not gonna make it over tonight.
迪恩  我一直努力对你友好点
You know, I've tried playing nice, Dean,
-但是我受够了  -等等  你是想告诉我
- But I think I'm done. - Wait, are you trying to tell me
你表面不讨好  内心更混蛋吗
that you're a bigger knob than you've been letting on?
我一直在这里  安安分分地做事
I'm the guy who's been here, doing my job.
你是谁  你以为我们需要你吗
Who are you? You think we need you here?
你在这里四处游荡  游手好闲
You walk around like you're playing pro tennis.
而你近来做的运动只是
Only action you seen lately
和你的淫娃女友上床而已
is between your slut girlfriend's legs.
你确定明天要和我们一起去吗
You sure you want to come with us tomorrow?
天有不测风云哦
Accidents happen.
别担心 伙计  我罩你
Don't worry, man. I got your back.
房子就在山那边
The house is just over the hill.
有十几个吸血鬼  还有始祖
About a dozen vamps and the Alpha.
我们只有一次机会解决这混蛋
We got one shot at this son of a bitch.
克里斯蒂安  你负责侧面攻击
Christian, take flank.
其他人跟着我和萨姆
The rest of you are with me and Sam.
迪恩  格温
Dean, Gwen...
你们俩扫尾  解决漏网之鱼
hang back, sweep any stragglers we flush out.
有问题吗  迪恩
Problem, Dean?
哪敢啊
No, sir.
要我跟个过气货一起扫尾
I'm in the rear with the reject?
好了  出发
All right, let's go.
别担心  没事的
Don't worry. It's fine.
这一点都不好  你就有事
No, nothing's fine. You're not fine.
走吧  去吧
Go. Go.
抱歉说你是"过气货"
Sorry about the "Reject" thing.
还听过更难听的呢
Ah, I've been called worse.
我有点厌倦扫尾的工作了
Just, uh, get sick of getting left behind.
大概因为我让他想起他的女儿吧
Think it's probably 'cause I remind him
谁知道呢
of his daughter or something.
你只是说出了自己的心声
Well, you just speak your mind.
那我就当你在夸我了
I'll take that as a compliment.
那绝对
You should.
不客气
You're welcome.
我们应该留守在这里
We're supposed to wait here!
迪恩
Dean!
萨姆
Sam!
好了  把他塞进去
Alright, get him in there.
塞进去  开下山
Get him in, drive this down.
你去哪里了
Where were you?
这边一切顺利吗
Everything all right here?
削了个逃兵的脑袋  没什么
Just, uh, chopped up a runner. No big deal.
你们呢
How'd it go?
有点难度  但还是搞定了一个始祖
Rough, but one Alpha down.
它在哪里呢
Where is it?
我想向它致以最后的敬意
Want to pay my last respects.
带些棉花糖  它已经在火上烧着了
Well, bring marshmallows. Already on the pyre.
刚才还行吧
Things go okay back there?
很好啊
Fine.
没什么奇怪的吗
Nothing weird?
我看到你们押着始祖走出来了  萨姆
I saw you walk that Alpha out the door, Sam.
就当我是疯了好了
Now, call me crazy...
但那绝对不正常
but that seems weird.
这样啊
Oh.
这样么
"Oh."
你不应该知道这事的
You weren't supposed to know about that.
-知道啥  -萨穆埃尔一直在这么做
- Know what? - It's just something Samuel's been doing.
抓住它们  带到某处
Catching things, taking them somewhere,
盘问信息
grilling them for info.
盘问
Grill.
你是说折磨吧
Torture, right?
瞒着我是他的主意么
And not telling me -- that was his idea?
不  是我的
No, it was mine.
为什么
Why?
实话吗
Honestly?
因为你会把事情搞砸
'cause you'd mess it up.
你会先开抢  后问问题
You shoot first, ask questions later,
但我们要一些情报
and we needed to ask questions.
我说  我不在乎你没有灵魂
You know, I-I don't care if you've got soullessness
还是得了要命的腮腺炎  兄弟
or the freakin' mumps, man --
你怎么那么看不清呢
You know better than this!
你还想找回你的灵魂吗
Do you even want your soul back?
这两件事有关联吗
How does that have anything to do --
你去过萨穆埃尔关它们的地方吗
Have you been to the place where Samuel takes them?
你参与过他们的盘问吗
I mean, have you been in on these interrogations?
没有  但我听说
No, but I hear --
他想要什么  目的又是什么
And what does he want? And why?
你不觉得这一切很可疑吗
And did it ever occur to you that this is really shady?
他是我们的外公
He's our grandfather.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊  相当赞的猎魔人
Yeah, a guy who talks a great game.
但你不能假设
But you can't assume that family means
他和我们一样重视家人
the same thing to him as it does to us.
他不是爸爸
He's not dad.
-你不明白  对吧  -什么
- You don't see it, do you?  - What?
你没有本性了
You've got no instinct.
我说  你真的是一团糟
I mean, you are seriously messed up.
-多谢  -我没在开玩笑  兄弟
- Thanks.  - I'm not kidding, man.
没人逼你跟我一起干活  好吗
Nobody's forcing you to work with me, okay?
但如果我们要一起干
But if we do this...
我来做主  我来指挥
I drive the bus, I call the shots,
所有事你都得向我汇报
and you tell me everything,
不管你觉得是否重要
whether you think it's important or not,
相信我  因为你根本分辨不出
because -- trust me -- you can't tell the difference.
你去跟着萨穆埃尔
Or, you know what, go -- go with Samuel.
看看结果如何
See how that goes.
自己把握
It's up to you.
萨穆埃尔
Samuel?
死孩子  记得敲门
Damn, kid. Learn how to knock.
你哥呢
Where's your brother?
走了
Gone.
走了  是什么意思
What do you mean, "Gone"?
他走了快一小时了
I mean he left about an hour ago.
我估计我俩再也无法统一立场了
He and I just weren't seeing eye-to-eye anymore I guess.
真糟糕
That's too bad.
我想入伙
I want in.
入伙什么
In?
参与盘问  所有的事
On the interrogations, on everything.
我可以帮忙
I can help.
这个家  这就是我要的生活
This family -- this is it for me now.
不管你需要什么  我都会照做
Whatever you need, I'll do.
-我知道  -很好
- Yeah, I know you will.  - Great.
但在解决你灵魂问题之前
But until we can figure out this soul business of yours,
我只要你保持现状
I need you to keep doing what you're doing.
-我能  -不行  你不能
- But I can -- - No. You can't.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好吧
Right.
你以为我不会回来了
You didn't think I'd come back.
我大概有六成把握
I figured 60/40.
萨穆埃尔没上钩
So, Samuel didn't take the bait.
所以我采用了后备计划
So I went with plan "B."
我们还有后备计划吗
We had a plan "B"?
我把他手机的全球定位系统给启动了
Fired up the GPS on one of his cellphones.
我们应该能跟踪他找到始祖
We should be able to track him right to the Alpha.
-老头子不会发现吗  -相信我
- The old man won't notice?  - Trust me.
他凹凸很久了
He thinks velcro is big news.
那里  找到他了
There. Got him.
死人血吗
Dead man's blood?
真聪明
Smart.
用吸血鬼驱除剂来封锁这里
Lock the place down with vamp repellent.
(无授权请勿入内)
在哪里
Where is it?
回答我
Answer the question.
它在哪里  我们要怎么找到它
Where is it? How do we find it?
嗷  住手  好疼
Ouch. Stop. That hurts.
这些
This --
与我们给你准备的大刑相比
This is club med compared to
这简直是天堂了
what we have planned for you.
我有的是时间跟你耗
I got -- I got all the time in the world.
巧了  我也是
Well, that makes two of us.
你们俩想整晚都这么藏着吗
Are you two going to hide all night?
出来吧  孩子们
Come on out, boys.
有什么我能帮忙的
How can I help you?
我们有几个问题问你  老滑头
We got some questions for you, skippy,
反正你哪也去不了
Since you're going nowhere fast.
话别说这么死
Don't be so sure.
是吗  我看锁得可是够死的呢
Yeah? Locked down pretty tight.
再加上流在你血管里的那些死人血
And with all that dead blood rushing through your veins,
估计你没那么多能量
not sure you got enough juice
用吸血鬼的念力召唤帮手吧
to fire up that psychic bat-signal of yours, do you?
没错
True.
确实没那么多能量
Not near enough juice for that...
迪恩
Dean.
我都不知道咱俩这么熟  可以直呼其名了
I didn't realize we were on a first-name basis.
咱们当然够熟
Of course, we are.
毕竟  你曾有那么一阵子
After all, you were my child...
是我的孩子
for a time.
迪恩  告诉我
Dean, tell me...
当吸血鬼的感觉爽吗
Did you enjoy it?
我才是提问题的人  你个吸血魔头
I'm asking the questions here, Fright Night.
当人类初学用火时
When your kind first huddled around the fire,
我便已在黑暗中生存
I was the thing in the dark!
你觉得现在你能伤到我吗
Now you think you can hurt me?
我有的是时间  而你们没有
I have all night, boys. You do not.
总之 不管你们想知道什么 我都悉数奉告
Anyway, I'm happy to tell you whatever you want to know.
-为什么  -为什么
- Why? - Why?
因为很快  我便会让你们血流成河
Because soon, I'll be ankle-deep in your blood,
吸尽你们的骨髓
sucking the marrow from your bones.
这么说真的是你了
So you're really it.
吸血鬼的祖先
The first of your species.
始祖
The very first.
但如果你是始祖
But if you're the first...
那又是谁创造了你
Who made you?
万物由来  皆有其源
We all have our mothers.
我也不例外
Even me.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
还有近来的吸血鬼数量激增是怎么回事
And what's with the big surge of vamps lately?
我是说  就好像--
I mean, it's like --
我们将要开战了
We're going to war.
为什么  怎么回事
Why? What's going on?
为什么萨穆埃尔把你带来这里
Why did Samuel bring you here?
你散发着阴冷的气息
You smell cold.
你没有灵魂
You have no soul.
真奇怪啊
What an oddity.
你感觉得到内心的空虚吗
Do you feel how empty you are?
没有灵魂是什么感觉
What is it like to have no soul?
-回答我  -你先说
- Answer my question. - You first.
别忘了你才是被关着的那个
You're the one in the cage.
灵魂这个东西啊
The thing about souls --
当然  假如你有的话
If you've got one, of course --
终有归宿
Is they're predictable.
你死后  上天堂或下地狱
You die, you go up or down.
但我们的种族会去哪里
Where do my kind go?
别跟这儿老和尚念经了  怪物
All right, enough with the sermon, freak.
我在回答你的问题
I'm trying to answer the question.
接着上面  若我们"怪物"死了
Now, when we "Freaks" die...
我们魂归何处呢
Where do we go?
不是天堂  亦非地狱
Not heaven, not hell.
那是哪儿呢
So?
欢乐谷吗
Legoland?
《神曲》都忘得差不多了吗  孩子们
Little rusty on our Dante, boys?
是炼狱
Purgatory.
炼狱  炼狱真的存在吗
Purgatory? Purgatory's real?
唉  你个猪脑子
Oh, stupid cattle.
当然存在
of course!
那里充满了像我一样
And it is filled with the soul of every hungry thing like me
曾行走于世的饥饿的灵魂
that ever walked this earth.
可这地方在哪儿  这才是真的谜
Now, where is it? That is the mystery.
这也是你们"善良的"外公
And that is what your kindhearted granddaddy
想要从我这里逼出来的
is trying to beat out of me.
萨穆埃尔把你带来
Samuel brought you here...
是想找出炼狱的所在吗
to find out where purgatory is?
我一直跟他说  这种事我怎么会知道
I keep telling him -- how would I know such a thing?
但他就是不肯放开我
But he refuses to untie me.
你很清楚那地方在哪儿
You know exactly where it is.
萨穆埃尔怎么会关心这个
Why does Samuel care about any of this?
他才不关心
He doesn't care.
他只是奉命行事
He does as he is told.
如果外公是傀儡
Well, if the old man's kermit...
那又是谁在操控他呢
Whose hand's up his ass?
哥儿几个  晚上好
Evening, guys.
知道吗  我以前白痴见多了
Wow, you know, I have seen some stupid in my time,
可真没见过你这么白痴的
But you take the crown.
找个破笼子就想把那大魔头关起来
Putting jaws in a fishbowl?
你觉得能有好结果吗
How do you think that's gonna end?
我不知道你在玩儿什么火
I don't know what kind of game you're running --
你以为我这是在玩儿吗
What, do you think I'm doing this for kicks?
我以为你是让这帮蠢货
I think you got the rest of
都觉得你是约翰·韦恩(西部片之王)
these feebs convinced that you're John Wayne.
所以无论你在做什么  在隐瞒什么
So whatever you're doing, whatever you're hiding...
都会把你和你身边的人拖进地狱
It's gonna put you and everyone around you in the ground.
嗨
Hi.
格温
Gwen.
我还以为咱俩有点特别的感觉呢
And I thought we had something special.
你怕我吗
Are you scared of me?
换做我  我会怕的
I would be.
来吧
Go ahead.
拿好武器
Grab your stuff.
我们还剩多少死人血
How much dead man's blood we got left?
始祖还有多久会完全恢复
How long till the alpha's 100%?
一小时  或许还不到
Hour. Maybe less.
我们得给他注入死人血  然后关回笼子里去
We need to get him dosed up and back in the cage.
不行
No.
什么叫"不行"
What do you mean, "No"?
我的意思是  我不知道你有啥大计划
I mean, I don't know what your big plan was,
但别想玩儿猫鼠游戏
But playing catch is not on the table.
-迪恩  -不把那东西脑袋砍掉
-Dean -- We take the thing's head off,
我们都会死在他手上
Or it kills us all!
你清楚得很
You know that.
好吧
Okay.
分头行动  逐间搜索
We split up. Clear every room.
只要有机会  就扎他一针
You get a shot, you take it.
虽然杀不了他
It's not gonna kill him, but
但会让他的速度减慢许多
dude will move a lot slower without any kneecaps.
如果我们能逃过这一劫  你  我和萨姆
And if we make it through this, you, me, and Sam
就要好好开次家庭会议了
are having one hell of a family meeting.
你觉得他跑出去了
You think he ran out?
不
No!
没有灵魂的孩子
The boy with no soul.
我给你准备了大餐
I've got big plans for you.
那讨厌的小灵魂真够碍事的
It's amazing how that pesky, little soul gets in the way.
但你就不用担心这个问题
But not for you.
你终究会成为一个完美的
You will be the perfect...
禽兽
Animal.
克里斯蒂安
Christian?
太精彩了
Well, that was dramatic.
克劳力
Crowley?
好久不见
Hello, boys.
这样的见面方式真够特别的
What an unexpected treat.
放了克里斯蒂安
Bring Christian back now.
-你说啥  -我侄子
- I'm sorry? - My nephew!
你刚植入恶魔灵魂的那个
The one you just crammed a demon into!
非也  他很久前就被附身了
Oh. No. I had him possessed ages ago.
真的  萨穆埃尔
Samuel, really.
我可关心我的作品了
I keep an eye on my investments.
等等  你俩认识
Wait. You two know each other?
没到基情的地步
Not in the Biblical sense.
更像是种生意伙伴关系
More of a business relationship, I'd say.
你是克劳力的走狗
You're Crowley's bitch.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
就是你想的那样
It's precisely what you think.
他给我抓的那个吸血鬼始祖
That Alpha he's caught me
为他赢得了不少好处
is getting him a gold star.
你啥时候开始在意吸血鬼了
Since when do you give a crap about vampires?
是从
Since, uh...
今天礼拜几  礼拜五吗
What's today -- Friday?
我想想 应该是从 还是关心你自己的事吧
Since, let's see -- mind your business.
你最好全说出来  克劳力
You may as well share with the class, Crowley.
我们知道你在找炼狱
We know you're looking for purgatory.
你们都听说了啊
So you heard about that?
对  你到底有什么企图
Yeah. You want to tell us why?
不是明摆着的吗
Isn't it obvious?
地盘  地盘  地盘
Location, location, location.
我是个开拓者
I'm a developer.
炼狱广阔无垠
Purgatory is vast,
却利用不足  而且毗邻地狱
underutilized, and hell-adjacent,
所以我想为我所用
And I want it.
-用来干什么  -你最好闭嘴
- What for? - Best shut your gob.
当手下的无权向老板提问
Employees don't question management.
-我们可不是你手下  -你们当然是
- We ain't your employees. - Of course you are!
而且已经当了好一阵子了  多亏了你们外公
Have been for some time now, thanks to gramps.
不然我留着他干嘛  对吧
I don't keep captain chromedome around for his wit, do I?
萨穆埃尔知道很多事情
Samuel knows things.
事实上  他比你们谁都知道的多
More than any of you, actually.
简直就是本活的百科全书
Walking encyclopedia of the creepy and the crawly.
而且我还知道
And I knew...
你俩一直执着于对家庭的忠诚
You two are so hung up on family-loyalty nonsense,
他说朝东  你俩绝不会朝西
He said jump, you'd get froggy.
够了  游戏结束了
Yeah, well, the game's over.
恐怕好戏才刚上演
Yeah, well, afraid not,
除非你不想再见到萨姆的灵魂了
Not if you want to see Sam's soul ever again.
别唬人了
You're bluffing.
告诉他们  萨穆埃尔
Tell them, Samuel.
是他把我和萨姆带回来的
He pulled us both back, me and Sam.
什么  你知道这事
What? You knew?
不可能  小卡说那不是
No, Cass says it takes big-time mojo
一般的咒语能办到的
to pull something like that off,
而你不过是个在十字路口晃悠的恶魔
And you're nothing but a punk-ass crossroads demon.
那是曾经
Was a punk-ass crossroads demon.
现在  我可是地狱之王
Now? King of hell.
相信我吧  我有那本领
Believe me, I've got the mojo.
我动动手指就能让萨姆的灵魂回归肉体
I snap my fingers, Sam gets his soul back.
或者  你要还跟我对着干
Or you can be...You,
萨姆就会被我推回黑洞里去
And I shove Sam right back in the hole.
真不敢想象那洞里的情景
Can't imagine what it's like in there...
而我的想象力可是一流的
And I can imagine so many things.
大家都清楚了吗
So, we clear?
我是老板查理  你们是我的娇娃
Me, Charlie... You, angels.
任务很简单  给我捕猎去
Job's simple enough -- bring me creatures.
食物链越顶端越好
Aim high on the food chain, please.
对大家都有好处
Everybody wins.
幸会了  回见
It's been a pleasure. See you soon.
该走了
It's time to go.
上车
Get the van.
你竟然任凭一个恶魔发号施令
You're letting a demon call the shots?
一切都没有改变
Nothing's changed.
我们继续猎魔  就这么简单
We hunt. Period.
别担心  我会搞定他
Don't worry about him. I'll take care of it.
你信不信我
You trust me or not?
回车里去  格温
Get the van, Gwen.
跟个恶魔合作
Working with a demon, huh?
你和我想的不一样
You're not who I thought you were.
孩子  你根本不了解我
You don't know anything about me, son.
到底是什么那么重要
So, what's so important
让你能委曲求全给阎罗王当小弟
that you're the king of hell's cabana boy, huh?
他到底给了你什么
What'd he offer you?
女人  金钱  还是头发
Girls? Money? Hair?
我有我的苦衷
I got my reasons.
你要动手的话  就来吧
You gonna make a move, go ahead.
否则怎样
Or what?
不怎样
Or nothing.
我不会对你们做任何事  迪恩
I'm not gonna do anything to you, Dean.
你俩
You boys...
是我的亲人
...You're my family.
所以在我看来  你们有两个选择
So the way I see it, you got two choices --
要么一枪嘣了你外公  要么闪开
Put a bullet in your grandfather or step aside.
他出卖了我们
He sold us out.
我知道
I know.
算了吧
Let it go.
凭什么
Why?
你走吧
Get out of here.
那现在怎么办
So, what now?
我们绝不能给克劳力当帮手
We can't work for Crowley.
你确定
Are you sure about that?
我想你没明白  恶魔永远心狠手辣
I don't think you understand. Demons bone you every time.
这我知道  真的
Oh, no, I get it. I do, believe me.
问题是
Just running the math --
我们还有别的路可走吗
Do we really have another choice?
我们可以一刀砍死他
We could stab him in his throat.
那我的灵魂怎么办
And get my soul back how?
我只是觉得  看来我们得跟他玩玩了
I'm just saying, seems like we got to play ball,
起码眼下只能这样了
At least for the moment.
我以前也没少做过傻事
I have done some stupid things in my time,
但从没给恶魔打过工
but punching a demon's clock?
听着  只要等到我们想出其他办法
Look, just till we find another way.
然后呢
And then?
然后我们就去追杀克劳力
And then we track Crowley down
让那混蛋得到他应得的报应
And give that son of a bitch what's coming to him.
你支持我吗  迪恩
You with me, Dean?